From Premium CodeCademy Class
Code remade by myself
---------------------------------------------------
---------------------------------------------------
I. GETTING STARTED WITH NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING
---------------------------------------------------
---------------------------------------------------

---------------------------------------------------
1.Intro to NLP
---------------------------------------------------
Look at the technologies around us:

Spellcheck and autocorrect
Auto-generated video captions
Virtual assistants like Amazon’s Alexa
Autocomplete
Your news site’s suggested articles
What do they have in common?

All of these handy technologies exist because of natural language processing! Also known as NLP, the field is at the intersection of linguistics, artificial intelligence, and computer science. The goal? Enabling computers to interpret, analyze, and approximate the generation of human languages (like English or Spanish).

NLP got its start around 1950 with Alan Turing’s test for artificial intelligence evaluating whether a computer can use language to fool humans into believing it’s human.

But approximating human speech is only one of a wide range of applications for NLP! Applications from detecting spam emails or bias in tweets to improving accessibility for people with disabilities all rely heavily on natural language processing techniques.

NLP can be conducted in several programming languages. However, Python has some of the most extensive open-source NLP libraries, including the Natural Language Toolkit or NLTK. Because of this, you’ll be using Python to get your first taste of NLP.
---------------------------------------------------
2. Text Preprocessing
---------------------------------------------------
"You never know what you have... until you clean your data."
~ Unknown (or possibly made up)

Cleaning and preparation are crucial for many tasks, and NLP is no exception. Text preprocessing is usually the first step you’ll take when faced with an NLP task.

Without preprocessing, your computer interprets "the", "The", and "<p>The" as entirely different words. There is a LOT you can do here, depending on the formatting you need. Lucky for you, Regex and NLTK will do most of it for you! Common tasks include:

Noise removal — stripping text of formatting (e.g., HTML tags).

Tokenization — breaking text into individual words.

Normalization — cleaning text data in any other way:

Stemming is a blunt axe to chop off word prefixes and suffixes. “booing” and “booed” become “boo”, but “sing” may become “s” and “sung” would remain “sung.”
Lemmatization is a scalpel to bring words down to their root forms. For example, NLTK’s savvy lemmatizer knows “am” and “are” are related to “be.”
Other common tasks include lowercasing, punctuation removal, stopwords removal, spelling correction, etc
---------------------------------------------------
3. Parsing Text
---------------------------------------------------
You now have a preprocessed, clean list of words. Now what? It may be helpful to know how the words relate to each other and the underlying syntax (grammar). Parsing is a stage of NLP concerned with segmenting text based on syntax.

You probably do not want to be doing any parsing by hand and NLTK has a few tricks up its sleeve to help you out:

Part-of-speech tagging (POS tagging) identifies parts of speech (verbs, nouns, adjectives, etc.). NLTK can do it faster (and maybe more accurately) than your grammar teacher!

Named entity recognition (NER) helps identify the proper nouns (e.g., “Natalia” or “Berlin”) in a text. This can be a clue as to the topic of the text and NLTK captures many for you.

Dependency grammar trees help you understand the relationship between the words in a sentence. It can be a tedious task for a human, so the Python library spaCy is at your service, even if it isn’t always perfect.

In English we leave a lot of ambiguity, so syntax can be tough, even for a computer program. Take a look at the following sentence:

I saw a cow under a tree with binoculars.
Do I have the binoculars? Does the cow have binoculars? Does the tree have binoculars?

Regex parsing, using Python’s re library, allows for a bit more nuance. When coupled with POS tagging, you can identify specific phrase chunks. On its own, it can find you addresses, emails, and many other common patterns within large chunks of text.
---------------------------------------------------
4. Language Models - Bag-of-Words Approach
---------------------------------------------------
How can we help a machine make sense of a bunch of word tokens? We can help computers make predictions about language by training a language model on a corpus (a bunch of example text).

Language models are probabilistic computer models of language. We build and use these models to figure out the likelihood that a given sound, letter, word, or phrase will be used. Once a model has been trained, it can be tested out on new texts.

One of the most common language models is the unigram model, a statistical language model commonly known as bag-of-words. As its name suggests, bag-of-words does not have much order to its chaos! What it does have is a tally count of each instance for each word. Consider the following text example:

The squids jumped out of the suitcases.
Provided some initial preprocessing, bag-of-words would result in a mapping like:

{"the": 2, "squid": 1, "jump": 1, "out": 1, "of": 1, "suitcase": 1}
Now look at this sentence and mapping: “Why are your suitcases full of jumping squids?”

{"why": 1, "be": 1, "your": 1, "suitcase": 1, "full": 1, "of": 1, "jump": 1, "squid": 1}
You can see how even with different word order and sentence structures, “jump,” “squid,” and “suitcase” are shared topics between the two examples. Bag-of-words can be an excellent way of looking at language when you want to make predictions concerning topic or sentiment of a text. When grammar and word order are irrelevant, this is probably a good model to use.
---------------------------------------------------
5. Language Models - N-Grams and NLM
---------------------------------------------------
For parsing entire phrases or conducting language prediction, you will want to use a model that pays attention to each word’s neighbors. Unlike bag-of-words, the n-gram model considers a sequence of some number (n) units and calculates the probability of each unit in a body of language given the preceding sequence of length n. Because of this, n-gram probabilities with larger n values can be impressive at language prediction.

Take a look at our revised squid example: “The squids jumped out of the suitcases. The squids were furious.”

A bigram model (where n is 2) might give us the following count frequencies:

{('', 'the'): 2, ('the', 'squids'): 2, ('squids', 'jumped'): 1, ('jumped', 'out'): 1, ('out', 'of'): 1, ('of', 'the'): 1, ('the', 'suitcases'): 1, ('suitcases', ''): 1, ('squids', 'were'): 1, ('were', 'furious'): 1, ('furious', ''): 1}
There are a couple problems with the n gram model:

How can your language model make sense of the sentence “The cat fell asleep in the mailbox” if it’s never seen the word “mailbox” before? During training, your model will probably come across test words that it has never encountered before (this issue also pertains to bag of words). A tactic known as language smoothing can help adjust probabilities for unknown words, but it isn’t always ideal.

For a model that more accurately predicts human language patterns, you want n (your sequence length) to be as large as possible. That way, you will have more natural sounding language, right? Well, as the sequence length grows, the number of examples of each sequence within your training corpus shrinks. With too few examples, you won’t have enough data to make many predictions.

Enter neural language models (NLM)! Much recent work within NLP has involved developing and training neural networks to approximate the approach our human brains take towards language. This deep learning approach allows computers a much more adaptive tack to processing human language.
---------------------------------------------------
6. Topic Models
---------------------------------------------------
We’ve touched on the idea of finding topics within a body of language. But what if the text is long and the topics aren’t obvious?

Topic modeling is an area of NLP dedicated to uncovering latent, or hidden, topics within a body of language. For example, one Codecademy curriculum developer used topic modeling to discover patterns within Taylor Swift songs related to love and heartbreak over time.

A common first step is to deprioritize the most common words and prioritize less frequently used terms as topics in a process known as term frequency-inverse document frequency (tf-idf). Say what?! This may sound counter-intuitive at first. Why would you want to give more priority to less-used words? Well, when you’re working with a lot of text, it makes a bit of sense if you don’t want your topics filled with words like “the” and “is.” The Python libraries gensim and sklearn have modules to handle tf-idf.

Whether you use your plain bag of words (which will give you term frequency) or run it through tf-idf, the next step in your topic modeling journey is often latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA). LDA is a statistical model that takes your documents and determines which words keep popping up together in the same contexts (i.e., documents). We’ll use sklearn to tackle this for us.

If you have any interest in visualizing your newly minted topics, word2vec is a great technique to have up your sleeve. word2vec can map out your topic model results spatially as vectors so that similarly used words are closer together. 
In the case of a language sample consisting of “The squids jumped out of the suitcases. The squids were furious. Why are your suitcases full of jumping squids?”, we might see that “suitcase”, “jump”, and “squid” were words used within 
similar contexts. This word-to-vector mapping is known as a word embedding.
---------------------------------------------------
7. Text Similarity
---------------------------------------------------
Most of us have a good autocorrect story. Our phone’s messenger quietly swaps one letter for another as we type and suddenly the meaning of our message has changed (to our horror or pleasure). However, addressing text similarity — including spelling correction — is a major challenge within natural language processing.

Addressing word similarity and misspelling for spellcheck or autocorrect often involves considering the Levenshtein distance or minimal edit distance between two words. The distance is calculated through the minimum number of insertions, deletions, and substitutions that would need to occur for one word to become another. For example, turning “bees” into “beans” would require one substitution (“a” for “e”) and one insertion (“n”), so the Levenshtein distance would be two.

Phonetic similarity is also a major challenge within speech recognition. English-speaking humans can easily tell from context whether someone said “euthanasia” or “youth in Asia,” but it’s a far more challenging task for a machine! More advanced autocorrect and spelling correction technology additionally considers key distance on a keyboard and phonetic similarity (how much two words or phrases sound the same).

It’s also helpful to find out if texts are the same to guard against plagiarism, which we can identify through lexical similarity (the degree to which texts use the same vocabulary and phrases). Meanwhile, semantic similarity (the degree to which documents contain similar meaning or topics) is useful when you want to find (or recommend) an article or book similar to one you recently finished.
